Jason Perkins

Builder of everything from games and simulations to content management systems, ETL platforms, internet and intranet applications, and open source tools across the desktop, mobile, and web. Adept cross-domain technologist with experience in the consumer, life sciences, imaging, energy, and insurance industries.

Experience

Senior Consultant, Insurance Technology Services (2015–Present)

For Industrious One Consulting (remote); Java, AWS (EC2, Lambda, S3, SQS, Aurora, Redshift)

The ITS Data Migration (ETL) group helps the insurance industry move from legacy mainframes to modern cloud-based solutions, pairing expert analysts with a proprietary data processing platform to create fully automated bespoke migrations with very high success rates.

- Conceived & delivered a major platform redesign, reducing implementation times and costs by nearly a full order of magnitude
- Developed a new component-based pipeline processing architecture, increasing platform flexibility and enabling new areas of business
- Provided technical leadership to small (3–5 person) project teams; coordinated delivery of multiple simultaneous client implementations
- · Spearheaded internal project and process documentation efforts

Consultant, Sony Computer Entertainment (2011–2017)

For Industrious One Consulting (remote); C, C++, C#, Lua

Collaborated with tool and technology groups to extend Premake (see Applications, below) with new features and support for SCE proprietary platforms.

- · Added a module system enabling development & distribution of third-party extensions
- Added ability to script new platform and architecture targets
- · Established new coding patterns, enabling core logic to be easily extended by modules
- Developed and documented best practices for Premake use on SCE projects
- Coordinated development work across SCE US & UK teams and the OSS community

Technical Lead, Blit Interactive, Inc. (2011–2013)

For Industrious One Consulting (remote); Unity, C#, Javascript, Facebook Graph, HTML5, Flash

Blit creates mobile and online 2D and 3D games for household brands such as National Geographic, Mercedes, Hallmark, BBC, Hot Wheels, and Hasbro.

- Crafted game, character, and UI logic for Unity (C#), Flash, and HTML5 (Javascript)
- · Created library of reusable components and services to accelerate new title development
- Built reusable backend platform to store player information, scores, saves, and replays
- · Added friend lists, challenges, high scores, and trophies on Facebook Graph API
- Delivered fun, well-received games on short time frames

Senior Engineer, NextDocs Corporation (2009–2011)

Direct hire; SharePoint 2007 & 2010, C#, Visual Studio TFS

NextDocs provides SharePoint-based document and quality management solutions for the life sciences: life-cycles, workflows, PDF renditions, digital signatures, and more.

- Full-stack development of existing and new SharePoint-based applications
- Provided agile (Scrum) process mentoring; introduced test-driven development with TypeMock
- · Led two development teams through a major end-of-year product release

Senior Consultant, AICPCU (2006-2009)

For Jacquette Consulting; Java, Javascript, C#, XML, XSLT, Documentum, Oracle

American Institute for Chartered Property Casualty Underwriters is an education and professional certification authority to the insurance industry. Our team of five led transition from paper to fully digital content authoring with granular reuse across print, online, marketing, and custom products.

- Led online authoring effort; coordinated work between AICPCU and external e-learning vendors
- Built easy to use markup and reuse tools for e-learning content authors
- · Developed DITA-based content schemas and product-specific transformations

Applications

Premake (2003-Present)

github.com/premake - C, Lua, Windows, macOS, Linux

Open source utility simplifying the process of software build configuration: generate projects for multiple toolsets, platforms, and languages from a single scripted definition with a simple and easy-to-read syntax.

- · Original author and current project maintainer
- 1,600+ stars on GitHub; listed in credits for Starcraft 2, Heroes of the Storm, Mass Effect

Musicality (2010-2019)

getmusicality.com - Electron, Objective C, Swift, Javascript, C++, Node.js, macOS, iOS

macOS desktop player for a dozen popular music streaming services (ex. Pandora, Spotify), featuring AirPlay streaming, system notifications, hotkeys, and remote controls.

- Custom implementation of Apple's AirPlay protocol, with multi-room streaming
- · Universal iOS remote control providing full control over playback, volumes, and AirPlay streaming
- Reached #1 in the Mac App Store Music category in 2012

Additional Experience

More information on these and other positions is available on request.

- Led development of educational grant management system (AstraZeneca, 2004–2006)
- Helped author an XML interchange standard for media advertising expenditure reporting (TNS Media Intelligence, 2004)

Education

BS, Computer Science Rochester Institute of Technology